Anup Limbu

111 St. Peters Road Reading, Berkshire, RG6 1PG Tel: 07926463181

Email: anup.thebe.limbu@gmail.com

Software Engineer

Personal Statement

I am a self-motivated and driven software developer, with proven background of over four years' experience in software design, analysis, development, testing and implementation. I am highly efficient in programming and problem solving. Always remain to be focused on the task at hand and have strived to give my best effort to accomplish any task presented. I am confident in my abilities and avidly seek to improve and learn ways to improve my skills and knowledge where possible on my own and/or as a team.

Key Skills & Competencies

- Working experience on software design, analysis, development, testing and implementation with agile/scrum SDLC.
- Working experience on embedded real time system and knowledge of VoIP/SIP/Call processing protocol and experience on SVN and Linux build system.
- Efficient in problem solving and ability to work diligently under pressure.
- Ability to learn processes and system quickly and adapt readily to changing technology.
- Good interpersonal skills and experience of working with different development teams, clients and vendors including business leaders Microsoft, Plantronics, Jabra, Microchip and Broadcom.

Language: C, C++, Go, PERL, RUBY RTOS: Embedded Linux, VxWorks

Operating System: Windows, Linux

Relevant Course Work: Data Structure, Computer Networks, Computer Architecture,

Operating System, OOPs Concept

Work Experience/ Training

1) Fidessa — Dukes Court, Woking, Surrey, United Kingdom

Software Engineer (December 2018)

- Development on market data for trade exchange using C++.
- Helping Fix message interaction with exchange with the changes in Brexit venues.
- Fix critical customer escalation bugs.
- 2) Riverbed Technology-- Maxis 1, Bracknell, Berkshire, United Kingdom

Software Engineer (June 2017 – October 2018)

- Worked on the Service Delivery Platform, Riverbed's next generation SDN/NFV platform using Agile/Scrum development.
- Built Micro services using Golang, Hashicorp stack (Consul. Vault, Nomad), packaged as Docker container.
- Worked on Role Based Access Control for services.

- 3) **Hitachi Data Systems** -- Oldbury, Bracknell, Berkshire, United Kingdom **System Software Engineer** (Jan 2017 May 2017)
 - Worked on hyper converged, scale out memory storage solution.
 - Integration of media wiki API for wiki pages using RUBY.
- 4) **Polycom Technology (R&D) Centre Pvt Ltd** -- Hyderabad, Telangana, India **Software Engineer** (July 2014 August 2016)
 - Worked on script to build updater and application binaries for Polycom phones to support production.
 - Worked on writing driver's codes and open source Linux kernel integration for legacy Polycom products.
 - Gatekeeper for the platform codes and worked on new features; core dump tracker, CPU utilization display, backlight and LEDs blink on call.
 - Worked in design and implementation of USB layer interface and new standalone products.
 - · Responsible for mentoring and training new joiner and interns and advising best practice
- 5) Ready My Order Technology and Co. -- Hyderabad, India *Technical Trainee* (30 April 2014 30 June 2014)
 - Worked on bug fixing and unit testing.
 - Modified existing app to correct errors, upgrade and improve performance overall.
- 6) **Zyoba Labs Pt. Ltd.** -- Kathmandu, Nepal *Internship* (30 May 2013 – 30 July 2013)
 - Rapidly prototyped new capabilities to confirm feasibility.
 - Oversee unit and integration tests to consistently deliver high quality features.
- 7) Nepal Telecom, -- Nepal Internship (1 June 2012 3 July 2012)
 - Prepared detailed reports concerning project specification and activities.
 - Consulted staff engineers to evaluate network failure and provide robust solutions.

Education & Credentials

- A) National Institute of Technology, Warangal, India (2010-2014)

 Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech.) in Electronics & Communication Engineering

 First class Honours
- B) St. Xavier's College, Kathmandu, Nepal (2007-2009) Intermediate in Science (ISc.), Tribhuwan University, Kirtipur, Nepal
- C) Certificate in C Programming (2007 2008)
 St. Xavier's College, Kathmandu, Nepal

Awards & Achievements

- Star Award Bravo, employee of milestone, Polycom Technology (R&D) Centre Pvt. Ltd. (2014, 2015)
- Subulu Gold Medal for all-rounder student, 2014 NIT Warangal
- University Outgoing Sports Man of the year, 2014 NIT Warangal

Participation in Engineering Workshop & Seminars

- Co-ordinator in ETHICAL HACKING workshop in Technozion'11 at NITW (2011)
- Participated in JAHAAZ event in Technozion'11 at NITW (2011)
- Event Manager for NRC- ROBO WARS during Technozion'12 at NITW (2012)
- Event Co-ordinator in Technozion'13 at NITW (2013)
- Event Co-ordinator in Spring Spree event at NITW (2014)

Membership in Professional Organizations

- Engineers Without Boarders (EWB) Member (2012- 2014)
- Electronics & Communication Engineering Association, NITW Joint Secretary (2012- 2013)
- Forum for International Student Affairs, NITW Joint Secretary (2012- 2013)